So Amanda Sills went on live to speak on
Jay-Z, man. She said,
um, class consciousness is the key to
real resistance. We f to get straight
into the video, but first, show some
love to the channel. Let's get it.
I want to simplify the conversation
around Jay-Z
because
a lot of folks are confused as to why
other folks have eye around Jay-Z,
right? They feel like he's being
targeted. They feel like he's being
attacked. Uh I saw someone literally
say, "Can he live?" I mean, there was a
song, right? [laughter]
Can I live? Um,
and so I just want to do a quick little
clarifying for folks.
There are essentially, in my opinion,
two types of people in this world.
People who want peace and people who
want power.
Again, people who want peace and people
who want power.
Um, I honestly don't know
why there are some people that want
peace and why there are some people want
p who want power. However, that has been
a constant
conflict for quite some time. There was
a time where that wasn't the case. Okay?
However, that is what it's been for
thousands of years now. People who want
peace and people who want power.
People who want peace are always going
to seek out methodology that is going to
create that. People who want peace are
going to make room and make space for
there to be growth, right? For there to
be calm, for there to be access. People
who want power are going to always
enforce scarcity,
right? Because scarcity determines these
people are up here. these people down
here. People who want power are always
going to align themselves with entities
that already have power. And people who
want power are going to willingly
support uh perpetuate and carry out
behavior that tries to shun those who
want peace.
So when we talk about Jay-Z as a person,
but also as a symbol, right?
We're looking at somebody who has
created uh a pathway for themsself that
aligns itself with power. And we also
see somebody who is used by that power
structure.
They are literally weaponized by that
structure to create scarcity that
disrupts peace.
So when people say things like, "Oh,
selective outrage about someone like
Jay-Z,"
that is somebody who said that, that is
somebody who wants power.
That is what somebody wants. Somebody
wants power. Because at the end of the
day, there is no need for power in
peace.
There's no there's no need for power in
There is alignment. There's community,
there's compromise, there's consensus,
there's no need
to reach for power.
So when someone says, "Why can't you
just let him live?" Well, the question
becomes, what is he doing that impairs
people from being able to live? And if
you are a billionaire,
you are attached
to a system that actively impairs
living.
Period.
Period. And he has aligned himself with
Beyonce to help protect his image
because so many folks absolve him of
that position because of their love for
Beyonce.
This is not an individual attack just on
him. This is a continued assessment of
the billionaire class and the ways in
which they operate that manipulate and
continue to position power over peace.
Okay.
And [clears throat] so
many of us
don't
So, someone here just asked, "Why aren't
we equally critical of Beyonce?" Well, I
don't know what circles you're in, but
the circles that I am in are equally
critical of Beyonce and Taylor Swift and
Elon Musk and Bill Gates and all the
other billionaires.
the circles that I'm in understand
that the concept of a billionaire while
you
while I
while we
are trying to figure out how to pay a
bill,
how to feed kids, how to pay for child
care, health care, medical care, etc.
is nonsensical.
It doesn't make sense that there would
be billionaires
when we are in scarcity.
So that explanation
is I think something that would be
helpful to folks when they're trying to
if if they are trying to genuinely
understand
what the issue is with Jay-Z. Why are
people having an issue with Jay-Z?
To be quite honest, many people will not
understand why they are where why there
are issue sorry many people will not
understand why there are issues with
Jay-Z because they may lack the context
of history. They may lack the context of
actual power structures.
And so when you don't have those
contexts, you know, it can seem like
impractical
like why why why are we caring about
this person? They're just doing music.
So someone here named Tammy Hurst says,
"Why do we need to hear this?" You know
what's always fascinating to me is that
there's such an there's such a desire to
stay in ignorance for so many people,
right? I'm a brilliant person. I am
someone that actually has spent time
with Daisy and Beyonce. I actually know
a lot, right? So, when I'm speaking, uh,
you get the opportunity or the choice to
listen to what I'm saying or not. No one
is forcing it upon you. You tapped the,
um, you tap the screen and this is what
I'm talking about. So, you don't
actually have to listen to anything I'm
saying. You get the choice to do so. And
if you don't want to listen to what I'm
saying, you can exit.
So, what I'm saying is trying to give
you all some context about class, right?
So, there's no war but class war. When
we're talking about someone like Jay-Z,
what we are doing is acknowledging the
difference in class and the ways in
which particularly black people and
artists are used
as weapons against the ruling class to
keep them confused, to keep them
repressed, to keep them suppressed, etc.
And when you understand history and you
understand resistance and you understand
power structures, you understand that
people are used, propped up and pillared
to be tools of res tools of repression
against your resistance.
My thoughts on Dame.
I mean, Dame is also a capitalist. You
know, they just were taking different
routes. I think, you know, at the end of
the day, Dame is like, I'm trying to get
money, but I'm not trying to have to
share it with these white people. Um and
um
I think you know when it to me it's like
Dame wanted to be popping but he didn't
he didn't want to be popping
uh by these white folks terms but
neither either way neither of them are
honest.
No we are not all capitalists. Like what
are you talking about?
We all live in patriarchy. That doesn't
make all of us patriarchal.
We live in a capitalist society. That
does not make us capitalists. That means
that we are forced to to exist in
capitalism.
That doesn't mean that's how you
actively exist in your value system. I
do not have a capitalist value system.
Someone said, "I like Dame." You don't
even know Dame.
Mhm.
>> He don't like the way the vest. He
tried. I tried it. He don't like it.
I tried the way the vest. He was like,
"Get the me now."
Exactly. Like non-consensually.
Like Cuba is literally trying their best
to not be capitalists and they're
forcing they're forcing them
they're literally sanctioning them to
death and now they're talking about
attacking them militarily
which is absolutely absurd.
[clears throat]
So I'm going to explain capitalism for
this person here who seems to not
understand the difference between
commerce and capitalism. Capitalism is
scarcity for the purpose of profit.
Capitalism is the continued expansion
for no without limitation of profit of
of profit systems. Profitering systems
that is capitalism. Me designing shirts
and offering them for sale does not make
me a capitalist.
It makes me an artist. It makes me a
merchant. Okay. I My prices are not out
of line with the uh market that exists.
My prices I have four books. They're all
available
everywhere. Um so
my prices are not representative of a
false sense of scarcity. Literally,
someone said yesterday, I just bought my
reasonably priced shirt from you. Thank
you. Um, my products are made with
quality. My products are also made by my
hand, right? Like they're my designs.
I'm not extracting them from some other
source that is not being properly
compensated. I am not ex I am not
getting them made by production sources
that are not being properly comp
compensated. So, no, this is from uh the
change company. So when I had someone
said you are you have a Patreon. You're
a capitalist. My Patreon is $5 a month.
My Patreon is $5 a month. No, you are a
capitalist when you use scarcity and
exploitation
in order to achieve profit.
>> Okay. Okay, man. Y'all let me know what
y'all think of the whole capitalism and
the patriarch and all them other words
she was saying. Y'all got to give me
some good comments because man, that's
some um that's some good debate talk
right there. But we out.